Jagila Garba

<u>Garbajagila@gmail.com</u> | 07514408348 My Portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced Senior Analyst with over 3+ years in analytics, process automation, visualisation, reporting, leadership skills, and stakeholders' communication to drive business success. Successful at responding to shifting business requirements and priorities in a systematic way. Proven record of accomplishment of enhancing data driven decision making.

TECHNICAL SKILLS: SQL, Big Query, Python, Statistics, Power BI, Tableau, Data Visualisation, Advanced use of Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, and Access), SAS Enterprise Miner & Base, SAP, Data Architecture, Dashboard building, Data Models and Pipelines, Apache Spark, Data Analysis, Google Analytics, Business Forecasting, Stored procedures, Online marketing tools monitoring.

SOFT SKILLS: Critical Thinking; Self-motivation; Problem Solving; Communication & Presentation Skills; Customer Service Management; Teamwork & Leadership; Intellectual Curiosity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Data analyst | VocTech Hub

August 2023 - Present

- Conducting surveys, collaborating and collecting primary and secondary data from potential learners, employers and industry experts to understand the demand for technical and soft skills for different stages of a data professional.
- Continuous research and collaborating with other internal and external stakeholders to understand the demographics and target market for data trainings.
- Developed curriculums for basic skills required for Data analysts.
- Conducted cohort trainings for over 50 individuals about using data analysis tools such as Excel, Python, SQL and Tableau.
- Created reports of research about data trainings and developed easy to understand dashboards using Tableau to aid the understanding of learner's progress and engagement with platforms.

Senior Data and Insight executive | Leicester City Football Club. Oct 2022 – July 2023

- Led the data team in conducting complex data analysis projects, ensuring timely and accurate delivery of insights to inform decision-making, especially for marketing campaigns.
- Performed basket analysis and identifying trends to produce insights of customer's purchasing behaviors which assisted with product discounts, linked offers using SSMS and Excel.
- Developed and maintained robust data pipelines, including data extraction, transformation, and loading (ETL) processes, improving data quality and efficiency using SSMS.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define key performance indicators (KPIs) and dashboards to monitor business performance. Created easy to understand reports and dashboards to aid understanding for various departments using SSMS, Tableau and

- Excel also presented data-driven findings and recommendations to senior management, resulting in data-informed strategic decisions.
- Maintained and Monitored data from multiple data sources such as GA4, Facebook ad manager, Data warehouse to aid informed decision making which helped in increasing online purchases on Match days by 15% also helped the club save over £30,000 in budgeting.

Forecasting Analyst | Unipart Rail

August 2021 - Oct 2022

- Communicated with internal stakeholders ensuring business requirements are met, especially in supply chain management using SAP
- Assessed, interpreted, and analyzed data in accordance with developing supportable demand forecast and reports layout using SSMS.
- Increased productivity by 25% in the project of converting reports into a new database.
- Performed root cause analysis and automated report to identify data issues within different databases.
- Reduced processing time by 50% through reconstructing and automating reports from Access database into SSMS.

Data Analyst | Artoas Global Services

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019

- Worked in Partnership with companies' departments (Sales, marketing, product management) to build effective strategies that ensure customer satisfaction.
- Ensured business requirements are met by communicating with internal and external stakeholders.
- Uncovered patterns, trends, and insights in large datasets which assisted sales and marketing departments cross sell products and services, this led to 10 – 20% increase in sales using Python.
- Performed data manipulation using pivot tables, V-Lookups, and formulas in Microsoft excel.
- Provided comprehensive reports with visualizations created with Python and Excel to senior business members.

EDUCATION

Google Certificate

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

Foundation of Business Intelligence and Data Models and Pipelines.

MSc Data Analytics (Distinction) – De Montfort University Leicester. Jan 2020 – June 2021 Modules taken include Data miming, Statistics, Big data.

VOLUNTARY WORK – Tutoring over 10 post graduate students to use SQL, SAS, Python, basic of data analytics which has helped improve their grades and understanding of the data analysis tools.

Reference available on request.